[ Halloween theme music ]
[ music continues ]
[ kids ] Black cats and goblins
and broomsticks and ghosts .
Covens of witches with all of their hosts .
You may think they scare me ,
you 're probably right .
Black cats and goblins on Halloween night .
Trick-or-treat !
[ owl hooting ]
[ crickets chirping ]
[ Judith ] My parents won 't be home until 10 .
[ boy ] Are you sure ?
We are alone , aren 't we ?
Michael 's around someplace ...
[ laughing ] Take off that thing .
- Let 's go upstairs . - Okay .
[ Judith laughing ]
Your hands are ... [ indistinct ]
[ tense music ]
[ ominous music ]
[ boy ] Look Judy , it 's really late . I gotta go .
[ Judith ] Will you call me tomorrow ?
[ boy ] Yeah , sure .
- [ Judith ] Promise ? - Yeah .
[ door closes ]
[ music continues ]
- [ clock chiming ] - [ Judith humming ]
[ tense music ]
Michael !
- [ dramatic music ] - [ Judith screaming ]
[ knife slicing ]
Michael !
[ screaming continues ]
[ music continues ]
[ man ] Michael ?
- [ thunder rumbling ] - [ rain pouring ]
[ lighting cracking ]
[ thunder cracking ]
Ever done anything like this before ?
Only minimum security .
I see .
The driveway 's a few hundred yards up on the right .
[ thunder cracking ]
[ nurse ] The only thing that ever bothers me is their gibberish .
When they start raving on and on ...
You haven 't anything to worry about .
He hasn 't spoken a word in 15 years .
[ nurse ] Are there any special instructions ?
[ Loomis ] Just try to understand what we 're dealing with here .
Don 't underestimate it .
Don 't you think we could refer to " it " as him ?
If you say so .
Your compassion 's overwhelming , Doctor .
[ thunder rolling ]
What do I give him when we take him in front of the judge ?
Thorazine .
He 'll barely be able to sit up .
That 's the idea .
[ nurse ] You 're serious about it , aren 't you ?
[ Loomis ] Yeah .
You mean you actually never want him to get out .
- Never ever . - [ thunder rolling ]
Never .
Then why we 're taking him up to Hardy county ,
- if we 're just gonna - - - Because that is the law .
Here we are .
- [ thunder crashing ] - [ Halloween theme music ]
[ nurse ] Since when do they let them wander around ?
Pull up to the main gate .
- Shouldn 't we - - - Go on , move !
[ thunder crashing ]
Stop here .
Shouldn 't we go on up to the hospital and - -
Wait !
[ tense music ]
[ car rattling ]
[ screaming ]
[ tires squealing ]
[ glass shattering ]
[ shouting ]
[ engine revving ]
[ thunder rumbling ]
Are you all right ?
- You all right ? - Yes , I 'm okay .
He 's gone , he 's gone from here !
The evil is gone !
I ... I gotta ...
[ thunder crashing ]
[ birds chirping ]
[ tense music ]
[ door closes ]
Don 't forget to drop the key off at the Myers ' place .
I won 't .
They 're coming by look at the house at 10 : 30 .
Be sure to leave it under the mat .
Promise .
- [ car door closes ] - [ car engine starts ]
[ music continues ]
[ Tommy ] Laurie !
[ Laurie ] Hi , Tommy .
Coming over tonight ?
Same time , same place .
Can we make jack-o-lanterns ?
- Sure . - And watch the monster movies ?
- Sure . - Will you read to me ?
Can we make popcorn ?
[ Laurie ] Sure , sure , sure .
[ Tommy laughing ]
[ music continues ]
[ Laurie ] You better hurry up .
How come you 're walking to school this way ?
My dad asked me to .
- Why ? - I have to drop off a key .
Why ?
Because he 's gonna sell a house .
- Why ? - Because that 's his job .
Where ?
- The Myers ' house . - [ Tommy ] The Myers ' house !
[ birds chirping ]
You 're not supposed to go up there .
Yes , I am .
Uh-uh , that 's a spook house .
[ Laurie ] Just watch .
[ deep breathing ]
[ suspenseful music ]
[ Tommy ] Lonnie Elam said never to go up there .
Lonnie Elam said that 's a haunted house .
He said awful stuff happened there once .
Lonnie Elam probably won 't get out of the sixth grade .
[ Tommy ] I gotta go . I 'll see you tonight .
- [ Laurie ] Bye . - [ Tommy ] Bye .
[ Laurie ] ♪ I wish I had you all alone ♪
- [ heavy breathing ] - [ Laurie ] ♪ Just the two of us ♪
♪ I would hold you close to me ♪
[ continues singing indistinctly ]
I 'm not responsible , Sam .
- Oh , no ... - I told them how dangerous he was !
You couldn 't have , two roadblocks and an all-points bulletin
- wouldn 't stop a five-year-old ! - Well he was your patient , Doctor .
If precautions weren 't strong enough , you should have told somebody .
I told everybody ! Nobody listened .
- There 's nothing else I can do . - You can get back in there
and get back on that telephone .
Tell them exactly who walked out of here last night ,
and tell them exactly where he 's going .
- Probably going . - I 'm wasting my time .
Sam , Haddonfield is 150 miles away from here .
Now , now , for God 's sake , he can 't drive a car !
He was doing very well last night !
Maybe someone around here gave him lessons .
[ engine starting ]
[ woman over PA ] Doctor Chance , please come to point C.
Doctor Chance , point C please .
[ woman ] And the book ends .
But what Samuels is really talking about here is fate .
You see , fate caught up with several lives here .
No matter what course of action Collins took ,
he was destined to his own fate ,
his own day of reckoning ...
[ eerie music ]
[ tense music ]
- Ma 'am ? - [ woman ] Answer the question .
Oh , um , Costain wrote that fate
was somehow related only to religion
whereas Samuels felt that ...
well , fate was like a natural element ,
like earth , air , fire , and water .
[ woman ] That 's right , Samuels definitely personified fate .
In Samuels ' writing , fate is immoveable like a mountain .
It stands , where man passes away .
Fate never changes .
- [ bell ringing ] - [ kids shouting ]
[ indistinct chattering ]
Leave me alone !
- He 's gonna get you ! - [ both ] He 's gonna get you !
[ bullies ] He 's gonna get you ! He 's gonna get you !
He 's gonna get you ! He 's gonna get you !
The Boogeyman is coming .
Leave me alone !
He doesn 't believe us .
Don 't you know what happens on Halloween ?
Yeah , we get candy .
[ bullies laughing ]
The boogeyman , ooh ! The boogeyman !
[ bullies ] The boogeyman , the boogeyman ,
the boogeyman , boogeyman , boogeyman !
[ bullies laughing ]
[ Halloween theme music ]
[ heavy breathing under mask ]
[ engine starting ]
[ music continues ]
[ heavy breathing continues ]
He 's on his way .
You gotta believe me officer , he is coming to Haddonfield .
- [ train bell ringing ] - Because I know him .
I 'm his doctor .
You must be ready for him .
If you don 't , it 's your funeral .
[ train horn blaring ]
[ tense music ]
[ girls chanting ] We 're from Haddonfield , couldn 't be prouder .
Can 't hear us now , we 'll yell a little louder .
We 're from Haddonfield , couldn 't be prouder !
- Can 't hear now - - - [ girl ] Oh , look at you .
Look at all the books you have .
You need a shopping cart to get home . [ giggles ]
[ girls chanting ] Hey Haddonfield !
[ Laurie ] Yeah , not for me .
You know it 's totally insane !
We have three new cheers to learn in the morning ,
the game in the afternoon , I have to get
my hair done at five and the dance is at eight .
I 'll be totally wiped out !
I don 't think get enough to do tomorrow .
Totally !
As usual , I have nothing to do .
It 's your own fault and I don 't feel a bit sorry for you .
Hey , Lynda , Laurie !
Why didn 't you wait for me ?
We did , 15 minutes .
You totally never showed .
That 's not true , here I am .
What 's wrong , Annie ? You 're not smiling .
I 'm never smiling again .
Paul dragged me into the boys ' locker room to tell - -
Exploring uncharted territory ?
It 's been totally charted .
- We just talked . - Sure , sure .
Old jerko got caught throwing eggs and soaping windows .
His parents grounded him .
He can 't come over tonight .
I thought you were babysitting tonight .
[ Lynda ] The only reason she babysits is to have a place to - -
Shit .
I have a place for that .
I forgot my chemistry book .
So , who cares ?
I always forget my chemistry book and my math book
and my English book and my ...
and let 's see my French book and ...
- [ Halloween theme music ] - [ Lynda ] Who needs books anyway ?
I don 't need books . I always forget all of my books .
I mean , it doesn 't really matter
if you have your books or not .
Hey , isn 't that Devon Graham ?
I don 't think so .
I think he 's cute .
[ Annie ] Hey , jerk !
Speed kills !
[ tires screeching ]
[ music continues ]
God , can 't he take a joke ?
You know , Annie , some day you 're gonna get us all into deep trouble .
Totally .
I hate a guy with a car and no sense of humor .
Well , are we still on for tonight ?
I wouldn 't want to get you in deep trouble , Lynda .
Oh come on , Annie .
Bob and I 've been planning on it all week .
All right .
The Wallaces leave at seven .
I 'm babysitting the Doyles .
It 's only three houses down . We can keep each other company .
Oh , terrific , I 've got three choices .
Watch the kid sleep , listen to Lynda screw around ,
or talk to you .
[ eerie music ]
[ indistinct chattering ]
[ indistinct chattering , laughing ]
What time tonight ?
I don 't know yet . I have to get out of
taking my little brother trick-or-treating .
Saving the treats for Bob ?
Funny , see you .
- Bye . - Bye .
[ sighs ]
[ eerie music ]
Annie , look .
- Look where ? - [ Laurie ] Behind the bush .
I don 't see anything .
That guy who drove by so fast , the one you yelled at .
Oh , subtle , isn 't he ?
[ music continues ]
Hey , creep !
Laurie , dear , he wants to talk to you .
He wants to take you out tonight .
He was standing right there .
Poor Laurie .
Scared another one away .
It 's tragic . You never go out .
You must have a small fortune stashed
from babysitting so much .
Guys think I 'm too smart .
I don 't , I think you 're wacko .
Now you 're seeing men behind bushes .
Well , home sweet home .
See you later .
- Bye . - Bye .
[ wind blowing ]
[ Laurie yelping ]
Excuse me , Laurie .
[ Laurie ] Oh , Mr. Brackett , I 'm sorry , Mr. Brackett .
Oh , I didn 't mean to startle ya .
That 's all right .
You know , it 's Halloween .
I guess everyone 's entitled to one good scare , huh ?
Yes , sir . Nice seeing you , sir .
[ girl ] Oh , stop !
[ girl laughing ]
- [ boy ] Trick or treat ! - [ kids ] Trick or treat .
[ kids laughing ]
Well , kiddo , thought you outgrew superstition .
[ wind blowing ]
[ eerie music ]
[ phone ringing ]
Hello ?
Who is this ?
[ phone ringing ]
Hello ?
[ Annie over phone ] Why 'd you hang up on me ?
Annie ? Was that you ?
- [ Annie ] Of course . - Why didn 't you say anything ?
You scared me to death .
[ Annie ] I had my mouth full , couldn 't you hear me ?
I thought it was an obscene phone call .
[ Annie ] Now you hear obscene chewing .
You 're losing it , Laurie .
I already lost it .
[ Annie ] I doubt that .
Listen , my mother is letting me use her car .
I 'll pick you up , 6 : 30 .
- Okay , bye . - [ Annie ] Bye .
Just calm down .
This is ridiculous .
[ eerie music ]
[ rock music playing on radio ]
Hurry up .
I 'm trying .
- ♪ Sha-na-na-na , sha-na-na-na ♪ - ♪ Let 's roll ♪
♪ Sha-na-na-na , sha-na-na-na ♪
- ♪ Let 's roll ♪ - ♪ Sha-na-na-na , sha-na-na-na ♪
We just have time .
Yeah . Judith Myers , Myers .
Row 18 , plot 20 .
Hey , you know , you know , every town has something like this happen .
I remember over in Russellville .
Old Charlie Bowles , about 15 years ago .
One night he - - he finished dinner ,
and he excused himself from the table
and he went out to the garage .
He got himself a hack saw .
And then he went back into the house ,
and he kissed his wife and his two children goodbye ,
- and then he proceeded - - - Where are we ?
Huh ? Oh , it 's right over here .
Yeah , Myers , Judith Myers .
I remember her .
Couldn 't believe it .
Such a young boy .
Well , are you lost ?
- [ graveyard keeper ] Why do they do it ? - [ eerie music ]
Goddamn kids .
They 'll do anything for Halloween .
Whose grave is it ?
Oh , I know , hm .
18 , 19 ...
Judith Myers .
He came home .
You still spooked ?
I wasn 't spooked .
- Lies . - I wasn 't .
I saw somebody standing in Mr. Riddle 's back yard .
Probably Mr. Riddle .
He was watching me .
Mr. Riddle was watching you ?
Laurie , Mr. Riddle is 87 .
[ Laurie ] He can still watch .
[ Annie ] That 's probably all he can do .
[ rock music playing on radio ]
What 's the pumpkin for ?
I brought it for Tommy .
I figured carving a jack-o-lantern would keep him occupied .
I always said you 'd make a fabulous girl scout .
- Thanks . - For that matter ,
I might as well be a girl scout myself tonight .
I plan on making popcorn and watching Doctor Dementia .
Six straight hours of horror movies .
Little Lindsey Wallace won 't know what hit her .
[ Laurie coughing ]
[ energetic music on radio ]
My dad ! Get rid of this .
- [ wind blowing ] - [ alarm ringing ]
- [ Laurie coughing ] - [ Annie ] Laurie , stop coughing .
What 's the matter with you ?
- [ Laurie ] Jesus . [ coughs ] - [ Annie ] Just be natural .
- There he is , just be natural , Laurie . - [ Laurie coughs ]
[ alarm continues ringing ]
Hi , Annie , Laurie .
Hi , Dad . What happened ?
- [ Brackett ] What ? - What happened ?
Oh , uh , somebody broke into the hardware store .
Probably kids .
You blame everything on kids .
Well , all they took was some Halloween masks , a rope ,
and a couple of knives .
Who do you think it was ?
It 's hard growing up with a cynical father .
- [ Brackett ] Aren 't you going to be late ? - Huh ?
- [ alarm shuts off ] - I said , aren 't you going to be late ?
He shouts too .
Bye girls .
- Bye , Dad . - Bye .
[ engine rumbling ]
Sheriff .
Pardon me , I 'm Loomis .
- Dr. Sam Loomis . - Leigh Brackett .
I 'd like to have a word with you if I could .
Ah , maybe a few minutes .
- I gotta take care - - - It is important .
10 minutes .
I 'll be here .
What 's the matter with you ?
I think he knew . I 'm sure he could smell it .
- No , he didn 't . - He did .
See the look on his face ?
[ chuckles ] He always looks like that .
What you gonna wear to the dance tomorrow night ?
I didn 't know you thought about things like that , Laurie .
You know you could ask somebody .
- [ Laurie ] No , I couldn 't . - Sure you could .
All you have to do is go up to somebody and say ,
" You wanna go to the dance ? "
You could do that , I couldn 't .
[ Annie scoffs ] Or you could ask Dick Paxter .
He 'd go out with ya .
- [ Annie chuckles ] - I 'd rather go out Ben Tramer .
Ben Tramer ?
I knew it !
[ laughing ] See , you do think about
things like that , huh , Laurie ? [ chuckling ]
- Shut up . - He 's cute .
- Ben Tramer . [ laughs ] - Shh !
[ Halloween theme music ]
[ heavy breathing under mask ]
- [ Laurie ] Okay . See you later . - [ Annie ] Bye .
[ heavy breathing continues ]
[ kids chanting ] Trick or treat , trick or treat ,
give me something good to eat .
Trick or treat , trick or treat ,
Trick or treat , trick or treat , give ...
[ eerie music ]
- [ Annie ] Hi . - [ Mr. Wallace ] Hi Annie , come on in .
- [ Annie ] How are you doing today ? - [ Mr. Wallace ] Fine , how are you ?
[ Annie ] What time do you want her in bed ?
[ Mrs. Wallace ] Be in bed by nine , okay ?
- Have a good night , dear . - [ Mr. Wallace ] Be a good girl .
- [ Annie ] Bye-bye . - [ Mrs. Wallace ] Bye-bye .
[ indistinct chattering ]
[ heavy breathing under mask ]
[ eerie music ]
Does anybody live here ?
[ Brackett ] No , not since 1963 when it happened .
Every kid in Haddonfield thinks this place is haunted .
[ Loomis ] They may be right .
[ door creaking ]
[ music continues ]
- [ Brackett whispers ] Look . - [ Loomis whispers ] What ?
What is that ?
[ Brackett ] It 's a dog .
Still warm .
He got hungry .
Come on . Could have been a skunk .
Could have .
A man wouldn 't do that .
This isn 't a man .
[ eerie music ]
[ floorboards creaking ]
It happened in here .
She - - she was sitting right here .
He could have seen her through this window .
Standing on the lawn .
He could have seen inside - -
[ glass breaking ]
[ chuckling ] He must think me a very sinister doctor .
Oh , I , uh ...
I do have a permit .
Seems to me you 're just plain scared .
Yes . Yeah , I-I am , uh ...
I met him 15 years ago .
I was told there was nothing left .
No reason , no conscience , no understanding
in even the most rudimentary sense of life or death ,
of ... of good or evil , right or wrong .
- [ eerie music ] - I met this ...
six year-old child with this blank , pale , emotionless face and ...
the blackest eyes , the Devil 's eyes .
I spent eight years trying to reach him ,
and then another seven trying to
keep him locked up , because I realized that
what was living behind that boy 's eyes
was purely and simply evil .
What do we do ?
He 's been here once tonight .
I think he 'll come back .
I 'm going to wait for him .
I still think I should notify the radio and television - -
No .
If you do that , they 'll see him on every street corner ,
they 'll look for him on every house .
Just tell your men to keep their
mouths shut and their eyes open .
I 'll check back in an hour .
[ crickets chirping ]
" ' How now , ' cried Arthur .
' Let no one pass this way without a fight ! '
' That so ? ' said the knight
in a bold and haughty manner . "
I don 't like that story .
I thought King Arthur was your favorite .
Not anymore .
Why do you keep them under there ?
Mom doesn 't like me to have them .
Laser Man .
Neutron Man . I can understand why .
Tarantula Man .
Laurie , what 's the boogeyman ?
[ phone ringing ]
Doyle residence .
- [ Annie over phone ] It 's me . - Hi Annie , what are you doing ?
[ Annie ] Making popcorn .
Having fun ?
Never mind , I 'm sure you are .
- I have big , big news for you . - [ dog growling ]
- [ dog barking ] - Oops .
Hold on a minute .
- [ barking ] - [ Annie ] Hi , Lester .
I 'm about to be ripped apart by the family dog .
[ laughs ]
- [ eerie music ] - [ dog barking ]
Lindsey , get this dog out of the kitchen right now .
[ eerie music on TV ]
[ dog barking ]
I hate that dog .
I 'm the only person in the world he doesn 't like .
[ laughs ] So , what is this big , big news ?
What would you say if I told you that you were
going to the Homecoming Dance tomorrow night ?
[ scoff ] I would probably say you got the wrong number .
[ chuckles ] Well , I just talked with Ben Tramer
and he got real excited when I told him how attracted you were to him .
Oh , Annie ...
Oh , you didn 't , please tell me you didn 't .
How could you do that ?
- I mean how you just call him ... - [ kids laughing outside ]
[ Laurie ] What do you mean it 's easy ?
I can 't believe this .
- I can 't tell you anything . - [ kids laughing ]
- [ eerie music ] - [ Laurie continues indistinctly ]
[ Laurie ] Please tell me you didn 't .
Oh , you didn 't .
- Laurie - - - Oh , I 'm so embarrassed ,
- I couldn 't even face him . - Boogeyman is outside .
- Laurie , he 's out there . - Hold on .
Laurie , the boogeyman is outside .
Look !
[ music continues ]
Tommy , there 's nobody outside .
Go watch TV .
It 's just Tommy .
Oh , please , Annie .
Why would you do that ?
- [ heavy breathing under mask ] - Look it 's simple .
You like him , he likes you .
All you need is a little push .
It won 't hurt you to go out with him , for God 's sake .
Shit !
No , no , I just made a mess on myself .
I gotta call you back .
Oh , yuck !
Lindsey , I need a robe .
[ eerie sounds from TV ]
[ eerie music ]
[ pot shattering ]
- [ heavy breathing under mask ] - [ Annie speaking indistinctly ]
[ Lester growling ]
[ Lester barking ]
Lindsey , Lester 's barking again
and getting on my nerves again .
[ Lester whimpering ]
Never mind .
I guess he found a hot date .
[ dramatic music ]
[ heavy breathing under mask ]
[ bright music on TV ]
[ dramatic music on TV ]
What about the jack-o-lantern ?
After the movie .
What about the rest of my comic books ?
After the jack-o-lantern .
What about the boogeyman ?
There 's no such thing .
Richie said he was coming after me tonight .
Do you believe everything Richie tells you ?
No .
[ chuckles ]
Tommy , Halloween night ,
it 's when people play tricks on each other .
It 's all make believe .
I think Richie was just trying to scare you .
I saw the boogeyman .
I saw him outside .
There was nobody outside .
- There was . - What did he look like ?
The boogeyman !
[ sighs ] We 're not getting anywhere .
All right . The boogeyman can only come out on Halloween night , right ?
- [ Tommy ] Right . - Well , I 'm here tonight .
I 'm not about to let anything happen to you .
- Promise ? - Promise .
Can we make the jack-o-lantern now ?
Let 's go .
[ eerie music ]
[ dog barking in distance ]
[ switch clicking ]
Oh , terrific .
[ sighs ]
[ door creaking ]
[ eerie music ]
Hello ?
Who 's there ?
Paul , is this one of your cheap tricks ?
Guess not .
No tricks for Annie tonight .
[ music continues ]
[ door creaking ]
[ doorknob rattling ]
[ grunts ]
Lindsey !
Lindsey , come out here !
[ muffled ] Lindsey , I 'm in the laundry room !
The door won 't open !
[ man on TV ] Spread out everybody .
We 're going to try to figure out the shape of the thing .
- [ dramatic music ] - [ man 2 on TV ] Holy cat .
- Hey . - [ man 3 on TV ] Yeah .
[ man 4 on TV ] Almost a perfect -
[ phone ringing ] - [ man 4 continues indistinctly ]
We finally got one .
[ man 5 on TV ] We found a flying saucer !
- [ eerie music ] - Oh , Lindsey , get the phone , it 's Paul .
- Lindsey ! - [ banging on door ]
Lindsey !
He called and I 'm in here .
[ objects rattling ]
[ indistinct chatter on TV ]
[ phone ringing ]
- [ man on TV ] I don 't know , Mr. Scott . - Hello ?
[ Paul over phone ] Hi Lindsey , this is Paul .
Is Annie there ?
Yes , she is .
[ Paul ] Get her for me , will ya ?
She 's washing her clothes .
[ Paul ] Look , just tell her it 's me , okay ?
- Okay . - [ man on TV ] What a story !
- Where 's ev - - Hey , Barn . - [ man 2 on TV ] Hold it , Scott .
Annie , Paul called !
[ Annie ] Ow !
You locked yourself in .
[ Annie ] I know .
Pull my foot , I 'm stuck !
[ Annie grunting ]
[ sighs ]
Now promise me you won 't tell anybody about this .
[ stomps foot ]
- [ crickets chirping ] - [ door closes ]
[ phone ringing in distance ]
[ phone continues ringing ]
She got stuck in the window . She 'll be right here .
- Hello ? - [ Paul over phone ] Hi , Annie .
- Oh , hi Paul . - [ Paul ] Stuck , huh ?
All right , cut it out . It can happen to anyone .
[ Paul ] Sure , stuck in the window .
Yeah , but I 've seen you stuck in plenty of other positions !
- [ eerie music ] - [ Paul ] My parents are gone .
Oh , that 's fabulous . When did they leave ?
- [ Paul ] About a half hour ago . - Oh , utterly fantastic .
So why don 't you just walk over ?
- [ Paul ] You come and pick me up . - Well , I can 't come now .
My clothes are in the wash .
- [ Paul ] You won 't need them . - Oh , shut up jerk .
God , I 've got a shirt on . That 's all you ever think about .
[ Paul ] I think that 's all you ever think about .
That 's not true , I think about lots of things .
Now why don 't we not stand here talking about them
and get down to doing them ?
[ man on TV ] Lock your doors ,
bolt your windows and turn off the lights .
Don 't go away ' cause here 's a scene - -
I 'm scared .
Well , why are you sitting here with all the lights off ?
- I don 't know . - Well , come on get your coat .
- We 're going to pick up Paul . - I don 't want to .
Look , Lindsey , I thought we understood each other .
I want to stay here and watch this .
Okay , if I can fix it so you can watch TV
with Tommy Doyle , would you like that ?
- Yeah . - Well , come with me .
- [ kids laughing ] - [ kid ] Come on , hurry up .
[ dramatic music ]
[ heavy breathing under mask ]
[ doorbell rings ]
[ TV playing indistinctly ]
- [ Annie ] Hi , Tommy . - Hi .
Come on in . We 're making a jack-o-lantern .
- Oh . - I wanna watch TV .
[ Laurie ] Annie , I 'm in here .
[ man on TV ] And now the horrifying conclusion
to The Thing .
Oh , fancy .
This has not been my night .
I spilled butter all over my clothes . They 're in the wash .
- I got stuck in the laundry - - - I wanna tell you something .
I 'd like you to call Ben Tramer and tell him you were just fooling around .
- I can 't . - Yes , you can .
No , he went drinking with Mike Godfrey
and he won 't be back until late .
You 'll have to call him tomorrow .
Besides , I 'm on my way to pick up Paul .
Wait a minute .
[ Annie ] If you watch her , I 'll consider
talking to Ben Tramer in the morning .
- Deal . - [ chuckles ]
- I thought Paul was grounded . - He was .
Old jerko found a way to sneak out .
Listen , I 'll call you in an hour or so , okay ?
Yeah .
- Bye . - Bye .
[ TV playing indistinctly ]
The old girl scout comes through again .
[ dramatic music on TV ]
[ Annie whistling ]
♪ My Paul , I give you all ♪
♪ No keys , but please , my Paul ♪
[ whistling ]
[ wind blowing ]
[ continues whistling ]
[ door shuts ]
♪ Oh , Paul ♪
♪ I can no longer stall ♪
♪ Really , Paul ♪
♪ My Paul ♪
[ whistling ]
[ finger squeaking ]
[ dramatic music ]
[ Annie yelps ]
[ shouting , gasping ]
[ heavy breathing under mask ]
[ horn honking ]
[ Annie gasping ]
- [ shouts ] - [ horn blaring ]
[ dramatic music ]
[ horn blaring ]
[ horn continues blaring in distance ]
Attention ! Captain to crew , stand by to reverse polarity .
Standard class A security will be maintained upon landing .
And until further notice all hands will wear a sidearm .
That is all .
Artificial gravity on .
- [ man 2 speaks indistinctly ] - [ man 1 ] Cut primary coils .
[ man 2 on TV ] Primaries cut , sir .
[ spaceship whirring on TV ]
[ whispers ] Lindsey !
Lindsey !
Where are you ?
[ dramatic music on TV ]
[ kids screaming ]
There he is , the boogeyman , he 's outside !
The boogeyman 's outside !
- The boogeyman 's outside ! - What 's wrong ?
- I saw the boogeyman , I saw him - - - Oh , Tommy stop it !
- But I really saw him ! - You 're scaring Lindsey .
- He 's - - [ shouting indistinctly ] - Tommy , stop it !
Now , there 's nobody out there !
There 's no boogeyman .
And if you don 't stop all this I 'm gonna have to turn off
the TV and send you to bed .
[ Laurie sighs ]
Nobody believes me .
I believe you , Tommy .
[ ship humming on TV ]
- I 'm not afraid . - Bull .
- [ boy 1 ] I 'm not . - [ boy 2 ] Then go in .
[ boy 2 ] Chicken .
Go ahead , Lonnie .
[ boy 2 ] Go in !
Hey !
[ in low voice ] Hey , Lonnie , get your ass away from there ...
Jesus .
- Are you all right ? - [ scoffs ] Yeah .
Well , nothing 's going on except kids playing
pranks , trick or treating , parking , getting high .
I have the feeling that you 're way off on this .
You have the wrong feeling .
You 're not doing very much to prove me wrong .
What more do you need ?
Well , it 's gonna take more than fancy talk to keep me up all night
crawling around these bushes .
I - - I - - I watched him for 15 years ,
sitting in a room , staring at a wall , not seeing the wall .
Looking past the wall , looking at this night .
Inhumanly patient .
Waiting for some secret , silent alarm
to trigger him off .
Death has come to your little town , Sheriff .
You can either ignore it or you can help me to stop it .
More fancy talk .
Doctor , do you know what Haddonfield is ?
Families , children , all lined up in rows ,
up and down these streets .
You 're telling me they 're lined up for a slaughterhouse .
They could be .
All right , I 'll stay with you tonight ,
just on the chance that you 're right .
And if you are right , damn you for letting him go .
[ Lynda laughing ]
Okay , this is what we 're gonna do . First , we go inside , right ?
Then we 'll just talk a little .
Then Annie will distract Lindsey , that 's when
we go upstairs to the first bedroom on the left .
- You got it ? - Okay . First I rip your clothes off ...
Don 't rip my blouse , it 's expensive , idiot .
Then you rip my clothes off ,
then we rip Lindsey 's clothes off .
- Yeah , I think I got it . - Totally . [ laughing ]
- [ can clattering ] - [ Lynda laughing ]
[ both laughing ]
[ Lynda ] No ! No ! [ laughing ]
Bob , put me down !
Put me down .
This is totally silly .
- [ Bob laughs ] - Put me down .
[ Lynda laughing ]
- Hey , it 's totally dark . - Yeah .
Hey , Annie !
Annie , we 're here !
[ Bob ] I wonder where they went .
Oh , Annie probably took Lindsey out for something .
[ door shuts ]
Hey , let 's look for a note .
Let 's don 't .
[ Lynda giggling ]
- [ eerie music ] - [ Lynda moaning ]
[ Tommy howling ]
[ all howling ]
He 's gonna get ya !
No , he 's not .
Hey , nobody 's getting anybody .
Stop scaring each other .
[ TV playing indistinctly ]
Everybody 's having a good time tonight .
All right , you guys , what 's next ?
[ Lindsey ] Let 's make more popcorn .
No , we 've had enough .
Why don 't we watch the rest of the movie ?
- Yeah . - [ Laurie ] Yeah .
[ man on TV ] All right , put it back on .
[ phone ringing ]
[ Laurie groans ]
Doyle house .
Hi Laurie , what 's up ?
[ Laurie over phone ] I 'm just sitting down for the first time tonight .
[ giggles ] Hey , is Annie around ?
[ Laurie ] No , I thought she 'd be home by now .
She went to pick up Paul .
Well , she 's totally not here .
She 's probably stopped off someplace .
Have her call me when she gets home , though .
I have Lindsey here and I want to know what time to put her to bed .
Okay , later .
- [ Laurie ] Have a good time . - We definitely will .
Bye .
Lindsey is gone for the night .
Hey , now that 's wonderful .
[ Lynda laughing ]
[ crickets chirping ]
[ TV playing indistinctly ]
[ Lynda moaning ]
[ phone ringing ]
[ Lynda ] Oh , shit !
- Not again . - [ Bob ] I can 't help it .
The phone keeps ringing .
[ Lynda ] Oh , I can 't keep you interested , huh ?
Just answer that damn phone .
I can 't , what if it 's the Wallaces ?
We 'd get Annie in trouble , you know .
Just take it off the hook .
[ both moaning ]
[ dramatic music ]
[ Lynda moaning ]
Oh , fantastic .
Totally .
Yeah .
- Want a beer ? - Yeah .
Is that all you can say ?
Yeah .
Go get me a beer .
I thought you were gonna get me one .
Yeah . [ giggling ]
I 'll be right back .
Don 't get dressed .
[ Lynda giggling ]
[ sighing ]
[ sighs ]
[ objects clinking ]
[ door creaking ]
Annie ?
- [ heavy breathing ] - Paul ?
Lynda , you asshole !
Okay , Lynda .
Come on out .
- [ dramatic music ] - [ Bob gasping ]
[ Michael breathing heavily ]
[ knife slicing ]
[ heavy breathing under mask ]
[ door creaking ]
[ nail file scraping ]
Well , did you get my beer ?
[ giggling ]
Cute , Bob , real cute .
[ heavy breathing ]
See anything you like ? [ chuckling ]
What 's the matter ? Can 't I get your ghost , Bob ?
[ laughing ]
All right , all right . Come on , where 's my beer ?
[ heavy breathing ]
Well , can 't you answer me ?
Okay , don 't answer me .
Boy , are you weird !
Well , I 'm gonna call Laurie .
I wanna know where Paul and Annie are .
This is going nowhere .
[ eerie music ]
[ phone ringing ]
Finally .
[ music continues ]
Hello ?
- [ heavy breathing ] - [ Lynda grunting ]
- Hello ? - [ Lynda grunting over phone ]
All right , Annie .
First I get your famous chewing ,
now I get your famous squealing ?
[ Lynda choking ]
Annie , you all right ?
- [ Lynda shouting , groaning ] - [ heavy breathing ]
Are you fooling around again ?
I 'll kill you if this is a joke .
- [ eerie music ] - [ Laurie over phone ] Annie ?
Annie ?
[ dial clicking ]
[ music continues ]
[ phone ringing in distance ]
[ softly ] Sleep tight , kids .
[ car engine shutting off ]
[ Loomis sniffs ]
[ Halloween theme music ]
[ eerie music ]
[ dog barking in distance ]
[ music continues ]
[ doorbell buzzing ]
[ door knocker clacking ]
Bob ?
Lynda ?
[ music continues ]
Annie ?
Lynda ?
Bob ?
[ door creaking ]
All right , Annie .
[ rustling ]
All right , meatheads , joke 's over .
Come on , Annie . It 's enough .
Most definitely stopped being funny .
Now cut it out !
You 'll be sorry .
[ eerie music ]
[ door creaking ]
[ Laurie whimpering ]
[ gasping ]
[ Laurie crying ]
- [ dramatic music ] - [ Laurie screaming ]
[ Laurie screaming ]
[ Laurie whimpering ]
[ crying ]
[ tense music ]
[ knife slashing ]
[ Laurie screaming ]
- [ thudding ] - [ Laurie groaning ]
- [ eerie music ] - [ Laurie whimpering ]
- [ intense music ] - [ Laurie whimpering ]
[ grunting ]
[ door rattling ]
No !
- [ wood crashing ] - [ Laurie whimpering ]
[ glass shattering ]
[ Laurie screams , whimpers ]
Help !
Somebody help me , please !
Somebody help !
Oh , God , help me !
Please !
Please , help me ! Oh ! [ groans ]
Help !
Oh , God , help me , please !
Hello !
Oh ! Oh !
Hello , help me !
Ma 'am , please help me !
Please !
Can 't you hear me ? !
Oh , God ...
[ screams ]
Help me , please !
[ Laurie whimpering ]
The keys !
Oh , the keys !
[ Laurie whimpering ]
Tommy !
- [ banging on door ] - Tommy , it 's me !
- [ grunts ] - [ pot shattering ]
[ music continues ]
Who is it ?
Tommy , open up , it 's me !
Yeah , okay .
Tommy please !
- [ banging on door ] - Tommy , hurry up !
Tommy , please ! Oh !
- Tommy ! Hurry up ! - [ banging on door ]
Tommy , please !
- Tommy , get upstairs . - What is it , Laurie ?
Tommy go back upstairs , get Lindsey ,
- lock the bedroom door . - I 'm scared !
- Do as I say ! - It 's the boogeyman - -
Hurry !
[ Laurie panting ]
[ buttons clicking ]
[ phone clattering ]
Oh , no ...
- [ eerie music ] - [ Laurie whimpering ]
Please , stop .
Please ...
- [ dramatic music ] - [ Laurie whimpering ]
[ Laurie whimpering ]
[ body thuds ]
[ Laurie panting ]
[ eerie music ]
[ Laurie groaning ]
[ music continues ]
[ sniffles ]
- Oh . - Where were you ?
I went to the Myers ' house .
I found the car , he 's here !
- Where ? - He 's three blocks down .
You go around the back of the houses , I 'll watch the front .
Go on !
[ music continues ]
Tommy ? Lindsey ?
Babies ...
We 're gonna take a little walk .
Was it the boogeyman ?
- I 'm scared . - There 's nothing to be scared of .
Are you sure ?
How ?
I killed him .
You can 't kill the boogeyman .
- [ kids screaming ] - [ eerie music ]
Get in there , come on , Tommy !
- Now , lock the door ! - [ lock clicking ]
[ Laurie panting ]
[ tense music ]
[ door rattling ]
[ Laurie whimpering ]
- [ wood crashing ] - [ gasps ]
[ Michael breathing heavily ]
[ music continues ]
[ grunts ]
[ Michael breathing heavily ]
[ knife slicing ]
[ Laurie panting ]
[ knife clatters ]
- [ knocking on door ] - Tommy .
Unlock the door .
Come here .
Now just listen to me .
I want you to go down the stairs
and out the front door .
And I want you to go down the street to the Mackenzies ' house .
I want you to tell them to call the police
and tell them to send them over here .
- Laurie ... - Now , do you understand me ?
- Yes . - Go do as I say .
[ eerie music ]
[ kids screaming ]
[ Tommy ] Get help ! Come on !
Come on !
[ kids screaming ]
[ music continues ]
[ intense music ]
- [ Michael breathing heavily ] - [ Laurie choking ]
[ Laurie shouting ]
[ shot firing ]
[ Laurie whimpering ]
[ Michael breathing heavily ]
[ shots firing ]
[ body thudding ]
[ dramatic music ]
[ crickets chirping ]
[ crying ]
It was the boogeyman .
As a matter of fact , it was .
[ Halloween theme music ]
[ Michael breathing heavily ]
[ heavy breathing continues ]
[ music continues ]